7209 Douglas Ave SE Snoqualmie, WA 98065 (425)-229-4433

<u>JoshuaEliTate@gmail.com</u>

linkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-torres-800491242

Github: https://github.com/JoshuaEliTate

Portfolio: https://643f3c52c63c4c1a95621e45--rainbow-travesseiro-2915cc.netlify.app

Joshua Torres

Full Stack web developer leveraging a background in customer service to provide great communication and patience. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University Of Washington Coding Boot Camp. Innovative problem-solver who is enthusiastic about developing apps with a primary focus on mobile design first. Strengths in teamwork, creativity, ingenuity, and building projects from ideas to finished Applications.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, CSS, HTML, SQL, NoSQL, GitHub, MongoDB, MERN Stack MySQL, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap,

Projects

SkillSwap -

Summary: SkillSwap is a website where you can post your skills that you want to teach, whether it's tutoring, cooking, or anything in between. While you or others can search for skills by category or skillname, to email the one who posted the skill.

Role: I worked mostly on the DB, frontend and backend, as well as the react functionality.

Tools: React, Apollo, Mongoose, JWT, GraphQl and Heroku.

https://skillswap100.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/JoshuaEliTate/SkillSwap

ChatDown -

Summary: ChatDown is a website in which you can create an account, post what you would like and comment on posts that have already been made.

Role: I was somewhat of the project manager of the group, working mostly on posting and grabbing the comments as well as nesting comments.

Tools: Sequelize, Handlebars, Doteny, Session, Joi

https://chatdown.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/JoshuaEliTate/ChatDown

ExpRecipe -

Summary: ExpRecipe is a website that allows a user to search for recipes and add their ingredients into a grocery list (utilizing Edamam API and local storage) and search for nearby grocery stores utilizing the Google Maps API.

Role: I worked with the Google Maps api as well as the local storage for the Ingredients

Tools: LocalStorage, CSS, JavaScript

https://joshuaelitate.github.io/ExpRecipe/ | https://github.com/JoshuaEliTate/ExpRecipe

Work Experience

Suite Restaurant/Lounge, Bellevue – APR 2021 - Present

Server/Host/Maintenance/Night Manager/Line Cook

- Took table orders, ran drink and food, as well as bussed my tables
- FloorBooked all reservations, including receiving deposits, and booking larger parties, as well taking care of customers when any problems arose
- General Maintenance (Painting, Repairs)
- Prepped food/Garde Manger/Friturier

Boxhouse, Seattle – May 2021 - June 2022 (closed)

Maintenance

- Manual Labor including Sanding, painting, moving, etc.
- Purchasing parts to maintain, repair, or replace company assets and equipment. (Building, furniture, TVs, etc.)
- General Cleaning, Vents, drains, floors, plumbing

Boyne Mountain Resorts, Snoqualmie Pass — OCT 2019 - APR 2022 (closed) Ski Instructor / Lift Operator

- Led 2-8 clients from beginners to experts specifically critiquing and teaching proper techniques of Skiing.
- Monitored Lift safety and conditions including lift bearings and maintenance.
- Operated Ski Lift, and managed large crowds.

Education

University of Washington, Seattle — 2022-2023

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

- Balanced and met multiple deadlines.
- University of Texas Austin, TX

Mount Si High School, Snoqualmie — 2017-2021

HighSchool Diploma

- Balanced and met multiple deadlines.
- Graduated with a High School Diploma.
- Worked on a variety of assignments and group projects.
- Started attending Bellevue College Junior Year

Bellevue College, Bellevue — 2019-2021

Associates of Arts & Science (60 of 90 credits)

- Obtained 60 credits, 2 quarters remaining to Graduate
- Achieved high grades in Advanced courses such as Precalc and Accounting

References

Lisa Olson, Office Manager

Suite Restaurant/Lounge

206-650-8805